typetester.org 2017-06-06

# Privacy policy | Typetester

**We don’t collect your personal information** , unless you provide it to us via web forms on this website (for example, when signing-up, signing-in, sending a message, subscribing to our newsletter etc.)

## Information we collect

If you register with us, communicate with customer support, send a message via this website or a third-party website (e.g. Twitter, Facebook), or add a comment to our blog post — you give us consent to collect, store, use and disclose (if required by law) the information that you’ve given to us as described in our Terms of Service and Privacy Policy. It may include your IP address, name, physical address, email address, phone number, credit card information, gender, occupation, and other demographic information.

## What else do we collect?

We collect technical information about your system to improve the service and to also prevent illegal activities. This includes IP addresses, OS and Browser versions and the times of visits. We collect font usage information and display it in a publicly available inspiration gallery. Registered user’s designs are private and require opt-in from the user to make it publicly accessible.

## Use of cookies

We use cookies to store your application and design settings, and to log visits to the Website be it in anonymous form (via Google Analytics). Read more about how we use cookies.

## Google Analytics

We track usage on our website via Google Analytics. The analytics.js JavaScript library is part of Google’s Universal Analytics and uses first-party cookies to distinguish unique users and throttle the request rate. Read more [how Google Analytics cookies work](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage?csw=1#analyticsjs).

## MailChimp Newsletter

We use a third party provider, MailChimp, to send newsletters. We also gather statistics around the opening of emails, link clicks etc., to help us monitor and improve our newsletter service. For more information, please see [MailChimp’s privacy policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).

## Access to personal information

If we do happen to hold information about you we will provide to you a copy of the information held and an explanation for why we are holding it. Any information we do hold will be kept private. Should you wish to see what information we hold about you, or to correct any mistakes please submit a request to us via our contact page.

## Disclosure of personal information

**We will not disclose any personal data without prior consent.** However, personal information will be exempt from any non-disclosure provisions when we investigate a complaint, especially where the disclosure of personal information is required by law, or in connection with preventing / detecting criminal activities. In such cases we will need to share the information in question with the relevant authorities, organizations and/or bodies.

## Links to other websites

This Privacy Policy doesn’t cover url’s within this website that link to other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on other websites that you visit.

## Contact us

If you need more information or have questions regarding our Privacy Policy please contact us.
